時は戦国、乱世の時代。
からくり人の住むジパング国では群雄割拠して合戦に明け暮れ、
からくり武芸者たちも勝利と栄光を目指してしのぎを削っていた。
そしていま、からくり武芸者ナンバー１を目指す、とてつもないヒーローが誕生した！
ムサシ、見参でござるだス！
からくり剣豪伝ムサシロード
男はいつでも　世界の真ん中で
いちばん　強くなる日を
AH! AH! 夢見て
心の刃　大空にふりかざし
冒険の旅の　幕を開ける
ジパング国を　さすらう剣豪
その名　からくりびと　ムサシ
GO! FIGHT!
鍔迫り合いの音が
眩しい人生
戦い　昨日よりも　今日　強い
BUGEI! 二刀流　ムサシ
明日は　輝くぞ
鍔迫り合いの音が
眩しい人生
戦い　思い切りと　静けさと
BUGEI! 二刀流　ムサシ
みけんが　きらめいた　ムサシ！！
무사시 일행은 마을 사람들을 괴롭히는 괴물, 츠치구모 퇴치에 힘썼지만,
Musashi's group did their best to take down Tsuchigumo, the monster that harasses the villagers,
여자 요술사, 오니히메의 요술에 당해 츠치구모의 먹이가 될 뻔했다.
but they almost became prey of Tsuchigumo under the magic of Onihime.
그러나 하늘의 도움인가, 신의 구제인가, 우시와카와 벤케이의 구원에 힘낸 무사시는
But thanks to the heaven, or the god or whatever, Ushiwaka and Benkei came to help and
비검의 소도(小刀), 천지환을 손에 넣었다.
Musashi finally got Tenchimaru, the secret small sword.
야마타노오로치 대결전이오
Yamata no Orochi, a Big Showdown
뭐라?
What?
센히메 일행이 코즈케를 건너서 아시카가에 간다고?
Senhime's group just passed by Kozuke and is now heading to Ashikaga?
예. 방금 들어온 정보입니다.
Yessir. It is a new information.
네이놈... 사천왕 둘에게까지 고배를 마시게 하다니, 못된 놈들, 무사시, 코지로.
You bastards... Gone through my two subordinates, Musashi and Kojirō?
이번에야말로 명을 끊어 주겠다.
Their life will be shortened this time.
카라쿠리 부엉이여, 우리 한조 부하의 사천왕 중 하나, 슈텐타이거에게 가라!
Karakuri Owl, go to Shutentiger, one of our four kings of Hanzō!
슈텐타이거여, 실수하지 마라. 어떻게 해서든 무사시와 코지로를 묻고 센히메를 잡아라.
Shutentiger, do not fail. Bury Musashi and Kojirō, and get Senhime no matter what.
이렇게나 봤는데도 괜찮은 남자가 별로 없네.
After all this travel, I can't find a good guy.
어라, 저 사람, 꽤나 근사한데.
Hey, that guy looks pretty nice.
저...
Hey...
음, 뭔 일이오?
What's up-dasu?
멋진 분. 이름을 알려주시지 않겠어?
Lovely gentleman, would you like to tell me your name?
미스터 코지로라 하오.
I am Mister Kojirō.
저, 사욘츠케라고 해. 어디서 차라도 같이 마시지 않을래?
I am Sayontsuke. Would you like to have a tea with me?
난 그딴 취미 없다!
I don't have a hobby like that!
차갑네... 짖궂어.
What a cold guy... How cruel.
아하하핳하핳, 어이, 미남!
Ahahahhahah, hey, you lady-killer!
흥!
Hmph!
슬슬 해가 지는군.
The sun is setting.
무사시, 언제까지 웃고 있을 거냐?
Musashi, shouldn't you done with laughing by now?
미안하오.
I'm sorry-dasu.
이 앞의 마을에 가서 묵을 수 있는지 이야기해보러 가라.
Go to the village ahead and ask them if there's a room to stay for a night.
또 잘난 척 명령하긴... 가오!
Proud of yourself again, eh? I'm going-dasu!
언젠간 되돌려 주겠소!
I'll pay all this back someday!
불만 많은 놈이군.
He sure complaints a lot.
어!
Oh!
뭔 일이냐, 무사시?
What's up, Musashi?
뭔 일이야?
What's up?
뭐야, 이게?
What the heck is this?
"어린 아가씨 대환영"
"All young unmarried girls welcome"
"1박 식사 등 전부 무료!"
"Free one night stop with free food!"
대단하잖아, 죄다 무료래!
Isn't it awesome? It's all free!
이건 바로 결정이오!
It's already settled-dasu!
센히메 님. 이건 좀 이상합니다.
Senhime, this definitely isn't right.
아무렴 어때? 나 배고파!
Does it matter? I'm hungry anyway!
자, 가자!
Let's go!
기다리시오, 센짱!
Wait for me, Sen-chan!
맛있어!
It's so good!
정말 최고! 내가 좋아하는 음식뿐이오!
It's the best! It's full of foods that I love-dasu!
무사시, 좀 조용히 먹지 못할까!
Musashi, eat silently!
국수는 이렇게 먹는 것이오!
This is how you eat noodles-dasu!
어이어이, 튀기잖아!
Hey, you're splattering it all over!
괜찮잖아? 코지로도 정말 시끄러워.
Isn't it alright? Kojirō, you're just being noisy.
공주님도 먹는 게 상스럽습니다!
Princess, you're eating vulgarly!
냅둬.
Leave me alone.
아, 잘 먹었소!
That was a great meal-dasu!
뭣이오, 저건?
What's that-dasu?
마을의 명물, 노래방이여.
It's the unique tradition of the village - Karaoke!
노래방?
Karaoke?
빈 통을 채워 노래부르고 춤추는 거라오.
You'll fill an empty jar and sing and dance with it.
오, 그건 재미있게 들리오!
That does sound interesting-dasu!
와, 좋소, 좋소!
It's great, great!
어이, 왜 할머니밖에 없을까?
Hey, I wonder why are there only grannies.
그러게요. 아까부터 젊은 여자의 모습이 하나도 안 보입니다.
I know. I am not seeing any young girls around here from some time ago.
여러분, 오늘 밤 저희 마을에 오신 걸 환영합니다.
Everyone, welcome to our village tonight.
아무것도 없지만 푹 쉬다 가시길 바랍니다.
Even thought nothing is here, we hope you can rest here.
이건 이 마을에 오래 전부터 전해져 오는 불로장생의 묘약, 100살까지도 젊고 기차게 살 수 있다고 전해져 옵니다.
This is a miracle drug of eternal youth from long time ago; with this, you can live young even when you're 100 years old.
100살까지이오?
Live more than age 100-dasu?
호호, 잘 듣는 수면제야.
This is one good sleeping pill.
자, 모두 안에 넣어라!
Now, put everyone inside jar!
왜 이런 짓을 하느냐!
What is the purpose of doing this?
-죄송합니다!
-용서를!
-We're sorry!
-Please forgive us!
뭐야? 야마타노오로치의 제물으로 처녀를 바친다고?
What? You're offering unmarried girls to Yamata no Orochi?
예. 한 달에 한번씩 처녀를 바치지 않으면 밭, 어린이, 마을 사람들을 덮치는 무서운 괴물입니다.
Yes. If we don't offer a girl every month, the monster will attack fields, children and villagers.
그러니까 우릴 속여서 그 대역으로 쓸 생각이었다니 용서할 수가 없잖아.
Nonetheless it's unforgivable that you were trying to use us instead of your usual victim.
노하심은 잘 알겠지만, 이 마을에는 처녀가 하나도 없습니다.
We understand that you are mad, but there is no more young girl left in this village.
나쁜 짓이라는 것은 알고 있었지만...
We knew it was a bad thing to do, but...
장난하냐!
Don't be stupid!
아, 잘 잤소.
That was a good sleep-dasu.
모두 뭔 일이오?
What's up, everyone-dasu?
죄송합니다. 그러나 할머니를 제물로 바치면 야마타노오로치가 화내서...
We apologize, but if we offer granny instead, Yamata no Orochi would get angry...
야마타노오로치?
Yamata no Orochi?
뭔가 다른 방법은 없는 건가! 마을 사람 전부 힘을 합해 퇴치한다던가.
Can't you do anything? Why not get rid of it combining all your powers?
그게 정말정말 저희 손으로 이길 수 있는 상대가...
That is, it isn't like that we can defeat it by ourselves.
알겠소. 우리에게 맡기시오!
Got it. Leave it to us-dasu!
무사시, 우리 목적이 뭔지 생각해라!
Musashi, don't forget about our objective!
아니, 야마타노오로치든 무슨 오로치든 내가 퇴치해 보이겠소!
No, I'll be the one who's going to take Yamata no Orochi or something down!
저, 정말입니까?
A- are you serious?
지팡구 제일의 무예가를 노리는 나이오! 두말은 하지 않소!
I am looking to become the number one Martial Artist of Jipangu! I do not take back my words-dasu!
무사시, 난 모른다!
Musashi, I won't care!
아, 좋소! 나, 뭐가 어떻든 해 보이겠소!
Sure then-dasu! I'll do this no matter what-dasu!
야마타노오로치... 츠치구모...
Yamata no Orochi... Tsuchigumo...
신이 다스리던 시대부터 명도 천공환, 천지환을 지키고 있다고 전해지는 괴물입니다.
They are monsters that are told to be protecting the sacred swords named Tenkūmaru and Tenchimaru.
그 괴물을 퇴치하면 그 명도가 손에 들어오는 것이오!
So by getting rid of those monsters, I will be able to have those excellent swords!
그 때야말로 무사시 님은 천하제일의 검호가 되겠죠.
When that time comes, Mr. Musashi, you'll become the best of the master swordsmen in the world.
나, 힘껏 해 보겠소!
I'll do my best-dasu!
그게 정말이라면 이렇게 감사할 일이 없습니다!
If that's true, there is nothing that we can be grateful any more than that!
보시는 대로, 부탁드립니다!
As you see, please do so!
재미있을 거 같아! 나도 응원할게.
Looks fun! I'll help you, too.
고, 공주님! 그런 위험한 일을!
P- Princess! That is to reckless!
괜찮아, 괜찮아! 무사시, 자, 가자.
It's alright! Don't worry! Musashi, let's go.
아, 기다려 주세요!
Please wait!
에이, 무사시 저 경망스러운 놈이!
Damn that luck-pusher!
어쩔 수 없지. 센히메를 지키는 건 내 임무.
Can't be helped. It's my duty to protect Senhime.
야마타노오로치는 술을 많이 먹는 괴물이었다.
Yamata no Orochi was a monster who drinks a lot of alcohol.
좋아요. 무슨 일이 있어도 여기서 나가면 안 됩니다!
Good. No matter what, do not leave this place!
뭐가 나올지 두근두근거려!
I want to find out what's going to come out!
뭐야, 저거!
What's that?!
무사시!
Musashi!
무사시, 일어나라!
Musashi, wake up!
일어나라, 무사시!
Wake up, Musashi!
무사시!
Musashi!
이놈!
You bastard!
이 무슨 딱딱한 놈이오!
What a tough guy-dasu!
센히메 님!
Senhime!
코지로, 무사시! 센히메는 가져가겠다!
Kojirō and Musashi! I'll take Senhime!
그러지 못할 테다!
Will not happen!
누구시오! 이름을 대시오!
Who are you?! Identify yourself!
슈텐타이거
Shutentiger
이하 사천왕의 하나, 슈텐타이거!
One of Four Iga Kings, Shutentiger!
센짱!
Sen-chan!
머리가 많은 뱀 따위에게 당하지 않겠소!
I won't be defeated by a snake with many heads-dasu!
젠장!
Dammit!
무사시! 이 녀석보다 센히메 구출이 먼저다!
Musashi! Rescuing Senhime comes first!
그래도 이 녀석을 쓰러뜨리지 않으면 도리가 없소!
But if we don't take this down, we have no hope-dasu!
어쩌오?
Now what-dasu?
장거리 무기와 같은 목을 봉하는 것은...
To seal the missile-like neck...
숲이다! 숲에 뛰어들어라!
Forest! Jump into the forest!
무사시! 여기서 결판을 내자!
Musashi! Let's finish this here!
알겠소!
Understood-dasu!
무사시!
Musashi!
이놈! 내 코테츠 돌려주시오!
You bastard! Give me back my Kotetsu!
그만두지 않으면 화낼 것이오!
Either you stop, or I'll get angry!
무사시, 위험하다! 질풍노도의 후반을 기다려라!
Musashi, watch out! Wait for the stormy latter half!
카라쿠리 검호전 무사시 로드
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
뒤다, 무사시!
On your back, Musashi!
괜찮나?
Are you alright?
내... 내 코테츠!
M- my Kotetsu!
아... 코테츠가...
My Kotetsu...
이놈!
You bastard!
뭔 짓이오!
What was that for-dasu?!
됐고 잘 들어라!
Never mind about that; just listen!
됐소!
We did it!
무사시!
Musashi!
무슨 일이오?
What's up?
이걸 봐라.
Look at this.
이, 이건 센짱의 피리!
T- this is Sen-chan's flute!
여기!
Here it is!
오, 이건 참말로 센히메의 물건. 이 주변에서 찾아라!
This really is of Senhime. Find her around this place!
센짱, 내가 꼭 구해 주겠소!
Sen-chan, I'll rescue you no matter what!
무사시! 딴짓하지 마라! 굳이 말하자면 너 때문에 이렇게 됐다!
Musashi! Pay attention! To be exact, it's all your fault!
난 불쌍한 마을 사람들을 그냥 둘 수는 없었소!
I couldn't leave those poor villagers like that-dasu!
네가 한 짓은 쓸데없는 참견이다!
What you did is nothing more than being a meddler!
뭣이오?!
What-dasu?!
그런 게 아니오!
That isn't true-dasu!
네이놈!
You bastard!
잠깐, 무사시!
Stop, Musashi!
항복이오?
Surrendering-dasu?
무사시, 던져봐라! 동굴이다!
Musashi! Throw it! It's a cave!
이런 곳에 동굴이라니 무슨 일이오?
What's going on; why is a cave here-dasu?
둔한 놈이군. 어떻게 봐도 분명 숨는 장소겠지.
What a blunt guy. Doesn't this place look like a hiding place to you?
그런 걸 알 리가...
Of course I don't know...
이곳에 있다는 것이다.
This means that it's here.
뭣이오, 이 거대한 곳은!
What is this huge place-dasu?
종유도다.
It's a limestone cave.
차것!
Cold!
조용히!
Silence!
야마타노오로치오.
Yamata no Orochi.
벌써 빠져나왔는가.
It escaped already?
슈텐타이거와 센히메 님은 어디에?
Where is Shutentiger and Senhime?
어쨌든 여긴 내게!
Anyway leave this to me!
아니오!
Nope!
내게 맡기시오!
Leave it to me!
뭐, 뭐냐, 그 모습은, 무사시!
W- what's up with that look, Musashi?!
오로치에게 바칠 술이오.
I'll let Orochi take this-dasu.
이것도 센짱을 위해서이오.
This is also for Sen-chan-dasu.
그런 무서운 얼굴 하지 말구, 마시고 싶지 않을까 하고 생각해서!
Quit making scary faces; I know you want to drink!
술 가져왔소. 마시시오.
I brought some alcohol-dasu. Have some.
자, 오로치쨩, 잘 생겼네. 거절말고 잘 먹어요.
How good-looking are you, Orochi-chan! Have as much as you want.
많이 마셔요. 많이.
As much as you want.
무예가 치고 엄청 잘 하네.
He's extraordinarily good at that for a Martial Artist.
어라?
Huh?
공주님!
Princess!
코지로!
Kojirō!
지금 바로 구해드리겠습니다.
I'm going to rescue you right now.
멍청한 놈. 뻔뻔히 나타나기는.
You fool! Do you think you can get away with this?
뒤에서 공격하다니 비겁한!
It is cowardly to attack from behind!
웃기지 마라!
Don't make me laugh!
어라, 호랑이 씨잖아?
Hey, aren't you Mr. Tiger?
네 아내다! 잘 지내나?
I'm your wife! Living well enough?
아내는 개뿔! 수준 떨어지는 변장하기는. 네놈 무사시지?
Wife, eh? That was one bad disguise! You bastard must be Musashi!
불에 뛰어드는 여름의 벌레라는 건 널 말하는군.
You are nothing more than a bug in summer flying into fires.
바보로 여기지 마시오! 센짱을 풀어주시오!
Don't treat me like an idiot-dasu! Let Sen-chan go-dasu!
오로치! 무사시를 먹어 없얘라!
Orochi! Eat up Musashi!
이번이야말로 물리쳐 주겠소!
I'll take you down this time-dasu!
코지로! 검 던져 주시오!
Kojirō! Throw me my sword-dasu!
달아나라, 달아나라! 곧 오로치와 하나가 될 터!
Run away, run away! You'll become one with Orochi!
여, 무사시!
Catch this, Musashi!
알겠소!
Got it!
어이, 오로치, 참수해주겠소!
Hey, Orochi, I'll cut your neck down-dasu!
어, 어라?
Oh?
으악!
Wah!
코지로! 천지환 주시오!
Kojirō! Give me my Tenchimaru!
나도 바쁘다! 알아서 뭐든 해라!
My hands are full now! Do something by yourself!
이제 끝이오.
It's now done.
젠장! 천지환만 있었으면 이런 오로치 따위 쉽게 물리쳤을 텐데!
Dammit! If with Tenchimaru, I'd already have taken down Orochi easily!
무사시!
Musashi!
센짱!
Sen-chan!
간다! 이럇!
Here it goes! Catch!
오로치는 이것만 있으면... 오시오, 오로치 놈!
With this, Orochi will be nothing... Come and fight, Orochi!
오, 오로치!
O- Orochi!
비검! 츠바메가에시!
Secret sword! Tsubamegaeshi!
예쁘오!
So pretty-dasu!
이것은 분명 천공환!
This must be Tenkūmaru!
뭐, 뭣이오?
W- what's going on-dasu?
젠장!
Damn!
멈춰라!
Stop!
잊어라, 무사시! 따라가지 마라!
Forget it, Musashi! Do not follow him!
모두 구했어.
Everyone is now saved.
무사시하고 코지로! 이 원한은 잊지 않겠다!
Musashi and Kojirō! I will not forget this!
무사시! 빨리 밖으로 나가라!
Musashi! Hurry up and go outside!
무사시!
Musashi!
슈텐타이거까지 당했단 건가... 무사시, 코지로. 다음엔 반드시 황천으로 보내 주겠다.
Shutentiger failed too... Musashi and Kojirō. I'll send you to the underworld next time.
감사합니다!
Thank you!
-조심하세요!
-조심해요!           -고마워요!
-Take care!
-Thank you!
잘 있어!
Take care!
그래도 슈텐타이거 놈, 왜 그렇게 마을 여자들을 모았을지 궁금하오.
But still, I wonder why did Shutentiger gathered those girl villagers so much.
매일 여자한테 둘러싸여 있으면 행복한가 보지.
I guess he's happy when he's surrounded by girls.
흥, 그냥 여자 밝히는 놈이었나. 무사시하고 꼭 닮았네.
Hmph, I guess he was just lustful. Just like Musashi.
뭐시라? 이랴!
What-dasu?! I'll get you!
멍청한 놈.
Idiot.
어허 참, 질리지도 않는구나, 무사시와 코지로.
Oh dear, aren't you tired of this yet, Musashi and Kojirō?
어쩄든 훌륭하게도 야마타노오로치를 쓰러뜨리고 천공환을 손에 넣은 무사시의 마음만은 신바람이 난다.
Anyway, Musashi is deeply encouraged, after taking Yamata no Orochi down and get his hands on Tenkūmaru.
센히메를 지키고 바야흐로 꽃보라가 흩날리는 사내의 활약도 쏜살같이!
He protected Senhime and his blossoming manly activities are at full speed!
그러나! 가는 곳에서 기다리는 것은 지옥인가 극락인가! 혹은 칼의 춤인가!
But nobody knows what's waiting for him - a heaven, or a hell? Or could it be the dance of swords?
カラのポケットに　ツキが
飛び込むことも　あるさ
おっきな声で　笑えば
あしたには　朝が来る
無くすものなんか　何もないさ
やっちゃえ！イケイケ！
手ぶらは　強いぜ
てなもんだ　のーてんきに行こう
人生　てなもんさ　チャンスが　ほら
しっぽを振って　追ってくるぜ
てなもんだ　のーてんきに行こう
未来も　てなもんさ　あしたが　ほら
両手ひろげて　笑ってるぜ
카라쿠리 요술사 고에몬도는 천하의 대도둑!
Karakuri magician Goemondo is the ultimate theif in the whole world!
성 지붕에 붙어 있는 금장식을 훔쳐가겠다는 예고장이 왔소.
He sent a notification that he's going to steal the gold decoration at the roof of the castle.
곧장 야간 파수를 하기로 결정했더니, 이 무슨 거대한 지네가 달려들었소!
When we decided to stay up all night to guard, a giant centipede came to attack us-dasu!
다음 이야기! 금으로 번쩍이는 도둑, 고에몬도이오
Next story! The Ultimate Thief of Shining Gold, Goemondo
질풍노도의 이도류이오!
It's a stormy dual blade-dasu!
다음 이야기
금으로 번쩍이는 도둑, 고에몬도이오
기대하세요!
Next Episode
The Ultimate Thief of
Shining Gold, Goemondo
Look forwards for it!